

Profile

Expert in software tooling and model based language engineering with significant experience in academia and industry. My expertise includes managing advanced software projects, international collaboration, graduate and undergraduate-level teaching, and R&D leadership, particularly in software productivity enhancement tools. Academically, I focus on developer tools, program analysis, domain-specific languages, and AI for software assistance. I have a strong record of leading research teams and integrating AI technologies with traditional software engineering

Employment

AIQ Frankfurt, Germany

Head of technology

November 2023 - Present

I lead the development of technology solutions to evaluate AI-based systems, ensuring they comply with the EU AI Act. My role encompasses both hands-on development and architectural design, as well as managing a diverse international team, including contractual employees and student assistants. Additionally, I provide expert consultancy in the field of AI system quality assurance.

HDA Darmstadt, Germany

Lecturer (Part-time)

November 2023 - Present

As a Lecturer, I engage with first-year Bachelor of Science students, helping them gain foundational knowledge in programming.

Technische Universität Darmstadt

Darmstadt, Germany

Researcher/ Lecturer

January 2020 – October 2023

I specialized in designing and constructing Al-based code models that prioritize reliability, explainability, and a deep understanding of software semantics. My research advanced API misuse detection and program security standards. Additionally, I teach graduate and undergraduate-level courses on programming languages and Al based software assistance, and I am a member of the university's hiring committee (Berufskomission).

Itemis AG Stuttgart, Germany

IT Consultant/Software Architect

December 2016 – January 2020

I designed and developed bespoke domain-specific languages and modelling tools, primarily catering to clients in the automotive and embedded systems industries. This involved understanding their unique needs, crafting precise language specifications, and building user-friendly tools to improve their operational efficiency and project effectiveness.

Goethe Universität Frankfurt, Germany

Research/Teaching Assistant

September 2013 – December 2016

Managed the foundations of programming languages lecture series while conducting research on addressing productivity issues associated with software evolution.

Universität des Saarlandes

Saarbrücken, Germany

Research/Teaching Assistant

September 2011 - September 2013

Contributed to the software engineering chair as a research assistant, supported graduate-level courses on software engineering and security, and aided the team in developing advanced program analysis tools for android malware detection.

Scantron Chennai, India

Software Development Engineer

September 2010 – September 2011

Developed and maintained a diverse software suite for the education sector, utilizing languages such as Script#, SQL, and JavaScript. Collaborated with a team of developers and testers to deliver high-quality software products.

Education

Goethe Universität Frankfurt, Germany

Ph.D. in Computer Software, Suma cum laude

2014-2017

Thesis - Combining user interaction and automation to evolve source code.

Universität des Saarlandes

University of Madras

Saarbrücken, Germany

Master of Science - MSc, Computer Science

2011-2014

Thesis - Android decompression chamber: A hybrid(static/dynamic) approach to detecting android malware.

Anna University

Chennai, India

Master of Computer Applications - MCA

2007-2010 Chennai, India

Bachelor of Science - BSc, Mathematics

2004–2007

Service

I have served on the program committee of several top-tier software engineering conferences including ECOOP, SLE, ISSTA, and OOPSLA.

Projects

jGuard: Java extensions that allow making APIs misuse resilient by design (MPS-based). Video demonstration

Transparent abstractions: Effective methods to simplify software reuse - Website **CogniCrypt**: State of the art in allow-listing based API misuse detection. Website

mbeddr: an extensible set of integrated languages for embedded software development - Website

Skills

Technical skills: Experienced in object oriented programming languages and building domain-specific languages/ modelling tools using XText and Jetbrains MPS. Skilled in static/dynamic program analysis and tooling for code assistance. Experienced in building cloud-based AI solutions on top of Azure. Proficient in software design, maintenance, and security.

Soft skills: Experienced in technical writing, presenting, and leadership. Strong collaborator with international and inter-disciplinary teams. Effective educator at graduate and undergraduate level.

References

- 1. **Prof. Dr. Christoph Reichenbach**: Relationship: Supervisor, Homepage, Contact: creichen@acm.org, christoph.reichenbach@cs.lth.se
- 2. Dr.Julia Lawall: Relationship: Supervisor, Homepage, Contact: julia.lawall@inria.fr
- 3. **Prof. Dr.Rodrigo Bonifacio**: Relationship: International Collaborator, Homepage, Contact: rbonifacio123@gmail.com
- 4. **Prof. Dr.Mira Mezini (use only when needed)**: Relationship: Managing Professor, Homepage, Contact: mezini@informatik.tu-darmstadt.de

PUBLICATIONS

Software tooling

- Fex: Assisted Identification of Domain Features from C Programs

Patrick Müller, Krishna Narasimhan, and Mira Mezini

In 21st IEEE International Working Conference on Source Code Analysis and Manipulation, SCAM 2021, IEEE, 2021, pp. 170–180

https://doi.org/10.1109/SCAM52516.2021.00029

- Cleaning up copy-paste clones with interactive merging

Krishna Narasimhan, Christoph Reichenbach, and Julia Lawall

In Autom. Softw. Eng., volume 25, number 3, 2018, pp. 627-673

https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-018-0238-5

- Combining user-interaction and automation to evolve source code

Krishna Narasimhan

PhD Thesis, Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 2017

http://publikationen.ub.uni-frankfurt.de/frontdoor/index/index/docId/42783

- Interactive data representation migration: exploiting program dependence to aid program transformation **Krishna Narasimhan**, Christoph Reichenbach, and Julia Lawall

In Proceedings of the 2017 ACM SIGPLAN Workshop on Partial Evaluation and Program Manipulation, PEPM 2017, ACM, 2017, pp. 47–58

https://doi.org/10.1145/3018882.3018890

- Copy and Paste Redeemed (T)

Krishna Narasimhan and Christoph Reichenbach

In 30th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering, ASE 2015, IEEE Computer Society, 2015, pp. 630–640

https://doi.org/10.1109/ASE.2015.39

- Clone Merge - An Eclipse Plugin to Abstract Near-Clone C++ Methods

Krishna Narasimhan

In 30th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering, ASE 2015, IEEE Computer Society, 2015, pp. 819–823

https://doi.org/10.1109/ASE.2015.103

API misuse

- FUM: A Framework for API Usage Constraint and Misuse Classification

Michael Schlichtig, Steffen Sassalla, Krishna Narasimhan, and Eric Bodden

In 2022 IEEE International Conference on Software Analysis, Evolution and Reengineering (SANER), 15.-18. March 2022, Honolulu, HI, USA, IEEE, 2022

https://doi.org/10.1109/SANER53432.2022.00085

- jGuard: Programming Misuse-Resilient APIs Simon Binder, Krishna Narasimhan, Svenja Kernig, Mira Mezini In Proceedings of the 15th ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Software Language Engineering, SLE 2022, Auckland, New Zealand, December 6-7, 2022, ACM, 2022 https://doi.org/ 10.1145/3567512.3567526
- Dealing with Variability in API Misuse Specification
 Rodrigo Bonifácio, Stefan Krüger, Krishna Narasimhan, Eric Bodden, Mira Mezini
 In 35th European Conference on Object-Oriented Programming, ECOOP
 2021, Aarhus, Denmark, July 11-17, 2021, Schloss Dagstuhl Leibniz-Zentrum für Informatik, 2021
 https://doi.org/10.4230/LIPIcs.ECOOP.2021.19
- BRAID: an API recommender supporting implicit user feedback
 Yu Zhou, Haonan Jin, Xinying Yang, Taolue Chen, Krishna Narasimhan, and Harald C. Gall

In ESEC/FSE '21: 29th ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, ACM, 2021, pp. 1510–1514

https://doi.org/10.1145/3468264.3473111

Al and Software Engineering

- Towards Trustworthy AI Software Development Assistance

Daniel Maninger, Krishna Narasimhan, and Mira Mezini

In IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering ICSE 2024 (NIER), Lisbon, Portugal, April 14-20, 2024, IEEE, 2024

https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.09126

- Evaluating and improving transformers pre-trained on ASTs for Code Completion

Marcel Ochs, Krishna Narasimhan, and Mira Mezini

In IEEE International Conference on Software Analysis, Evolution and Reengineering, SANER 2023, Taipa, Macao, March 21-24, 2023, IEEE, 2023

https://doi.org/10.1109/SANER56733.2023.00096

- Towards Code Generation from BDD Test Case Specifications: A Vision

Leon Chemnitz, David Reichenbach, Hani Aldebes, Mariam Naveed, **Krishna Narasimhan**, and Mira Mezini

In CoRR, abs/2305.11619, 2023

https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2305.11619

- Impact of programming languages on machine learning bugs

Sebastian Sztwiertnia, Maximilian Grübel, Amine Chouchane, Daniel Sokolowski, **Krishna Narasimhan**, Mira Mezini

In AISTA 2021: Proceedings of the 1st ACM International Workshop on AI and Software Testing/Analysis,

Virtual Event, Denmark, July 12, 2021, ACM, 2021 https://doi.org/10.1145/3464968.3468408

- NerdBug: automated bug detection in neural networks

Foad Jafarinejad, Krishna Narasimhan, and Mira Mezini

In AISTA 2021: Proceedings of the 1st ACM International Workshop on AI and Software Testing/Analysis, ACM, 2021, pp. 13–16

https://doi.org/10.1145/3464968.3468409

Software security

- Exploring the use of static and dynamic analysis to improve the performance of the mining sandbox approach for android malware identification

Francisco Handrick da Costa, Ismael Medeiros, Thales Menezes, João Victor da Silva, Ingrid Lorraine da Silva, Rodrigo Bonifácio, **Krishna Narasimhan**, and Márcio Ribeiro

In Journal of Systems and Software, 183, 111092, 2022

https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jss.2021.111092

- To Fix or Not to Fix: A Critical Study of Crypto-misuses in the Wild

Anna-Katharina Wickert, Lars Baumgärtner, Michael Schlichtig, **Krishna Narasimhan**, Mira Mezini In IEEE International Conference on Trust, Security and Privacy in Computing and Communications, TrustCom 2022, Wuhan, China, December 9-11, 2022, IEEE, 2022

https://doi.org/10.1109/TrustCom56396.2022.00051